<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Chinese Traditional Dress</string>
    <string name="hanfu_description">Hanfu is the traditional clothing of the Han Chinese, the ethnic majority of China. With a history of more than 3,000 years, Hanfu has evolved in style with the changing dynasties. Each dynasty had its own unique characteristics while inheriting elements from its predecessors. Typically composed of a robe, shirt, and skirt or trousers, Hanfu is noted for its elegant lines and wide sleeves. The flowy design represents the aesthetic of harmony, echoing the fundamental philosophy of Confucianism. Despite its decline during the Qing dynasty, a recent cultural resurgence has seen Hanfu gain popularity once again, especially among young people who are keen to reconnect with their cultural heritage.</string>
    <string name="cheongsam_description">The cheongsam, also known as qipao, originated in the 1920s Shanghai. With its high neck and thigh-high slit, the cheongsam elegantly combines traditional Chinese elements with Western fashion. The cheongsam gained worldwide attention in the 20th century as it symbolized the modern, independent Chinese woman. This garment is particularly popular during special occasions, such as weddings or Chinese New Year celebrations. Custom-made cheongsams that fit perfectly are a symbol of luxury and sophistication.</string>
    <string name="tang_suit_description">The Tang suit often refers to a type of jacket with a squared collar and Chinese knot buttons, popularized in the late Qing Dynasty and early Republic of China era. However, the term \"Tang Suit\" also denotes clothing styles of the Tang Dynasty (618-907), a period renowned for its openness to foreign influences and fashion-forward innovations. The Tang dynasty was one of the cultural pinnacles in Chinese history, and the clothing of this period was colorful, elaborate, and influenced by cultures along the Silk Road.</string>
    <string name="zhongshan_suit_description">The Zhongshan suit, also known as the Mao suit in the West, is a style of male attire named after Sun Yat-sen (also known as Sun Zhongshan), the founder of modern China. The Zhongshan suit was Sun\'s reinterpretation of Western-style clothing, intending to promote a sense of Chinese identity and nationalism. It became standard attire for Chinese men after the establishment of the People\'s Republic of China in 1949. With its simple design, the Zhongshan suit symbolizes equality and collective identity.</string>
    <string name="shenyi_description">Shenyi, literally meaning \"deep robe,\" is considered the most classic form of Hanfu clothing, with a history that can be traced back to the Zhou Dynasty (1046-256 BC). The Shenyi is a one-piece garment that consists of a top and skirt sewn together. It was widely worn by scholars and officials in ancient China. Shenyi represents the perfect unity of yin and yang, embodying the profound philosophy of balance in Chinese culture. Although it\'s not commonly worn in daily life today, it\'s often seen in traditional rituals or ceremonies to honor the ancestors.</string>
    <string name="pienfu_description">Pienfu is a ceremonial costume in a set of two pieces - a tunic-like top and a skirt-like bottom. It was considered formal attire in ancient China, particularly during the Han Dynasty (202 BC - 220 AD). The outfit was often elaborately decorated, and it was typically worn by the royal family and nobility on important occasions such as court ceremonies. The Pienfu symbolizes the grandeur and solemnity of the Chinese royal court.</string>
    <string name="changao_description">The Chang\'ao, literally translated as \"long coat,\" is another traditional form of Hanfu. It is characterized by its high collar, crossed collars (left over right), wide sleeves, and a sash at the waist. Chang\'ao was favored by women in the Tang Dynasty (618-907) and was often paired with a Ruqun (see below). The versatility and convenience of Chang\'ao have made it popular among different classes in ancient Chinese society, and it is also frequently seen in classical Chinese dramas and operas.</string>
    <string name="ruqun_description">Ruqun is a type of Hanfu that consists of a blouse (Ru) and a wrap-around skirt (Qun). It\'s one of the most iconic styles of Chinese traditional clothing, especially for women. The design of Ruqun varies based on the dynasties, but the basic form has remained the same for thousands of years. Ruqun is often accompanied by a silk shawl or a Chang\'ao. The elegant and flowing style of Ruqun showcases the grace and gentleness of Chinese femininity. Today, Ruqun is popular in traditional festivals, cultural events, or Hanfu movements.</string>
    <string name="daxiushan_description">The Daxiushan, or \"large sleeve robe\", is a type of Hanfu clothing that was popular during the Tang Dynasty (618-907). This style is distinguished by its wide and flowing sleeves, and it was typically worn by noblewomen during that period. The expansive sleeves were not only a fashion statement, but also showcased the wearer\'s grace and elegance, especially during dance performances. The Daxiushan represents the Tang Dynasty\'s prosperity and cultural openness, as the fashion during that time was heavily influenced by multicultural exchanges along the Silk Road.</string>
    <string name="yisan_description">The Yisan is another traditional Chinese dress dating back to the Han Dynasty (206 BC - 220 AD). Characterized by a square collar, loose sleeves, and a sash to tie at the waist, this outfit was worn by both men and women, often paired with high boots. In many ancient paintings, hunters, herders, and even noblemen are depicted wearing Yisan. Today, Yisan is an essential part of Hanfu revival movements and is often seen in historical dramas and cultural festivals.</string>
    <string name="daopao_description">The Daopao, or Taoist robe, is the traditional dress of Taoist priests. It\'s a long robe, typically in a plain and understated design, reflecting Taoism\'s values of simplicity and harmony with nature. However, some Daopao are adorned with intricate embroideries representing Taoist symbols. The history of Daopao traces back to the Song Dynasty (960-1279), and it is still worn today by Taoist priests during religious ceremonies. The Daopao signifies the spiritual wisdom and tranquility of Taoism, a key element of Chinese philosophy.</string>
    <string name="banbi_description">Banbi, also known as a \"half-arm garment\", is a style of traditional Chinese jacket with short sleeves. It was popular during the Tang and Song Dynasties (618-1279). The Banbi was usually worn over a long-sleeved undershirt and paired with a skirt or trousers, making it a versatile piece of clothing suitable for both casual and formal occasions. Different classes and professions, such as scholars, officials, and commoners, wore Banbi in various materials and designs. The Banbi showcases the pragmatic yet stylish side of Chinese fashion, reflecting the everyday life in ancient Chinese cities.</string>
    <string name="huadian_description">The Huadian, also known as \"flower plaque\", is a traditional Chinese facial adornment, usually a piece of red paper or silk cut into various designs and applied on women\'s foreheads. Emerging in the Tang Dynasty (618-907), this trend reached its peak during the Ming Dynasty (1368-1644). It was not merely a fashion statement but also a symbol of marital status: different designs signified whether a woman was married or single, or if she belonged to the court. Despite fading out of fashion over the centuries, the Huadian has been revived in recent years, especially among fans of Hanfu and traditional Chinese culture, showcasing the enduring charm of Chinese aesthetics.</string>
    <string name="changshan_description">Changshan, literally \"long shirt\" or \"long gown\", is a traditional Chinese dress worn by men. Its origins can be traced back to the Qing Dynasty (1644-1912) when the Manchu people ruled China. Changshan usually covers the body from neck to ankle, with a high collar and side slits starting from the waist. It\'s typically worn with a belt to create a fitted look. Although less common in modern times, the Changshan experienced a revival in the 20th century and has become a symbol of Chinese cultural identity, especially during festivals and formal occasions. It also gained international recognition through prominent figures like Dr. Sun Yat-sen, who wore a modified version known as the Zhongshan suit.</string>
    <string name="aoqun_description">Aoqun is a traditional Chinese outfit that consists of an \"ao\" (a blouse or jacket) and a \"qun\" (a skirt). It is believed to date back to the Han Dynasty (206 BC-220 AD), and it was a standard outfit for women for many centuries. The ao was typically a front-buttoning blouse, while the qun could be a pleated or a-line skirt. The designs and decorations of the aoqun evolved throughout different dynasties, reflecting changes in fashion trends and cultural aesthetics. Despite the advent of modern clothing styles, the aoqun remains an iconic representation of traditional Chinese women\'s clothing, seen at cultural events, period dramas, and Chinese opera performances.</string>
</resources>
